<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feature
      id="ECG_SensorAndLab"
      label="ElectroCodeoGram EclipseSensor with ECG Lab"
      version="1.0.0"
      provider-name="Frank Schlesinger (Frank@Schlesinger.com)">
   <install-handler library="installer.jar" handler="org.electrocodeogram.installer.Installer"/>

   <description url="http://www.electrocodeogram.org">
      This feature provides a plugin that acts as a sensor inside Eclipse
collecting &quot;micro-process&quot; event data. It is part of the ElectroCodeoGram
framework for &quot;micro-process&quot; recording and analysis. The &quot;micro-process&quot;
is the sequence of very fine steps a programmer takes while working.
Analysis of the &quot;micor-process&quot; is falling into the domain of
empirical software engineering, with the goal to make software
processes better and to minimize defect rates.
The sensor plugin collects &quot;micro-process&quot; events like the opening
of a file, the running or building of an application and even
textual changes in active documents. The events are then sent
to the ElectroCodeoGram&apos;s ECG Lab process, where they can be
analysed and stored into file system files for instance.
The ECG Lab comes along with this feature and the sensor plugin
is configured to initiate the communication with the ECG Lab
on its own.
If you have any questions, feel free to ask Frank@Schlesinger.com
   </description>

   <copyright>
      (c) 2005 Frank Schlesinger (Frank@Schlesinger.com)
   </copyright>

   <license>
      ElectroCodeoGram Software User Agreement
23th October, 2005
The ElectroCodeoGram (ECG) is licensed under the GNU General
Public License (GPL).
See http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.html
Applicable Licenses:
The ElectroCodeoGram sensor plugin for
Eclipse and the ECG Labare built upon a number of other open
source or free
technologies and products.  Here is a list of those products
with links to their licenses.
HackyStat: ECG reuses parts of the HackyStat project&apos;s software.
HackyStat is licensed under GNU General Public License.
http://www.hackystat.org/hackyDevSite/doc/LicenseInfo.html
Apache Xerces2: Is part of the ECG Lab&apos;s XML based event validation
mechanism. Apache Xerces2 is licensed under the Apache 2.0 license.
http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
OfficeLnFs: Is part of the ECG Lab&apos;s graphical user interface-
OfficeLnFs is licensed under a BSD style license.
http://officelnfs.sourceforge.net/License.txt
JGraph: Is part of the ECG Lab&apos;s graphical user interface-
JGraph is licensed under a GNU Lesser Public License (LGPL).
See http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl.html
IT IS YOUR OBLIGATION TO READ AND ACCEPT ALL SUCH TERMS
AND CONDITIONS PRIOR TO USE OF THIS CONTENT.
   </license>

   <url>
      <update label="ElectroCodeoGram Update Site" url="http://www.electrocodeogram.org"/>
   </url>

   <requires>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui.ide"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui.views"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.jface.text"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui.workbench.texteditor"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui.editors"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.core.resources"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.core.runtime"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.core.runtime.compatibility"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.jdt.core"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.jdt.junit"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.jdt.ui"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.osgi"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.debug.core"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.update.ui"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.core.boot"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.update.core"/>
   </requires>

   <plugin
         id="org.electrocodeogram.sensor.eclipse.ecg.sensorshell"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <data
         id="../sensor.properties"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"/>

</feature>
